[{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"1. The protagonist of a novel set in this city is repeatedly told to “hug it the bear” in reference to a dancing bear named Kano, which he must hug before he can receive a secret message. In 2010, a novel set in this city was withdrawn from the English syllabus of a university in this city because of the grandson of a nationalist politician complained that it unfavorably portrayed his grandfather’s party. The escaped Australian bank robber Lindsay Ford lives in this city in Gregory David Roberts’ autobiographical novel Shantaram. The unnamed “city by the sea” where the widow Dina hires two tailors to sew patterns for Au Revoir Exports in A Fine Balance is a clear representation of this city. For 10 points, Rohinton Mistry’s novel Such a Long Journey is critical of the right-wing Shiv Sena party, which has a strong influence on the Bollywood film industry in what city? ","answer":"ANSWER: Mumbai [or Bombay] <World Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"8. For 10 points, name this Leon Uris novel about the creation of Israel, titled for the second book of the Bible. ","answer":"ANSWER: Exodus <American Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"3. This leader presided over the last of the \"who cares\" riots, where naked or cross-dressing citizens took to the streets in mob violence. In order to improve his country's military readiness, this leader banned the breeding of any horse not large enough to serve in the cavalry and had all Kiso stallions castrated. Over 100,000 people contributed free labor to the first version of a building honoring this ruler, whose rebuilt form is the center of Culture Day celebrations. His government's deflationary policies to pay back foreign debt gave rise to the Freedom and People's Rights Movement, a group that ultimately succeeded in forming a national diet. During his reign, the top knot hairstyle went out of favor and his country's overseas ambitions were restrained by the Triple Intervention. His government replaced han land divisions with prefectures and promulgated the Charter Oath. For 10 points, name this Japanese emperor who names an eponymous \"restoration\" following the Tokugawa Shogunate. ","answer":"ANSWER: Meiji Emperor [or Meiji the Great; or Mutsuhito; Meiji-taitei] <World History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"4. William Judd financed his unpaid position supervising this structure by taking photographs in his mobile darkroom. Rather than buy a new set of curtains, Cecil Chubb purchased this structure as a gift for his wife, making him the last private owner of it. Edmund Antrobus constructed a much-hated barbed wire fence around this structure and later threatened to sell it to an American millionaire if the government didn't pay him for it. Henry Browne made himself the first \"custodian\" of this place and sold souvenir replicas of it. In 2019, Richard Madgwick found that pigs had been brought from hundreds of miles away for slaughter in this place. In the 1960s, Gerald Hawkins hypothesized that this structure was a “computer” used to predict astronomical events. William Danby’s replica of this structure was named for the druids he mistakenly thought built it. For 10 points, name this ancient monument in Wiltshire, England. ","answer":"ANSWER: Stonehenge <European History> 4/18/2019 Tiebreakers/Replacements - Google Docs https://docs.google.com/document/d/1lPxg-Ujut4_rc4dN7YKfx840YfEyyRpzssmOHBMNks8/edit 3/7 ACF Nationals 2019 | Packet: Tiebreakers/Replacements |Page 3 "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"5. This letter names an undesirable side reaction in radical polymerization which results in the scission of a primary free radical. An effect named for this letter stabilizes the intermediate of the Sakurai reaction. A transition from the M to the K shell is named for this letter in Siegbahn notation. Trans-spanning ligands or bulky alkyls such as neopentyls are used to prevent a reaction named for this letter, which is effectively the reverse of migratory insertion of an alkene. This letter names a stabilizing form of hyperconjugation caused by the presence of a silicon atom. Alkene complexes can be formed by the elimination of a hydride at the position named for this letter. Alanine is the only amino acid which naturally occurs in an alternative configuration in which its amino group is located at this position. The Claisen condensation results in an ester with a ketone at this position relative to the ester. For 10 points, name this letter applied to carbons found two carbons away from a functional group. ","answer":"ANSWER: beta <Chemistry> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"6. A camp built outside this nation’s capital by the Pentecostal Redeemed Christian Church of God includes water treatment plants and its own electric system that is capable of supporting millions of worshippers who regularly gather for Holy Ghost services. A sacred grove dedicated to a fertility and water goddess is dotted with sacred buildings that have peaked, forward-jutting awnings. This country’s most fundamentalist group is led by a man whose nickname translates to “specialist of tawheed;” that group was founded by Mohammed Yusuf. One of this country’s few remaining sacred groves lies outside of Osogbo. Practitioners of a traditional religion in this country may practice divination with shells or a chain of nuts; that divination is called Ifa. For 10 points, name this country that is home to the Yoruba and has large Christian and Muslim populations, the latter of which includes the highly radicalized Boko Haram. ","answer":"ANSWER: Federal Republic of Nigeria <Religion> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"7. In an essay partly titled for this man, Richard S. Hill analyzed his contemporary work and proposed that it would begin an evolutionary process from inscrutability to the “system of the future.” This man wrote that “one must acknowledge that there was no light before the Lord said: ‘Let there be Light’” in an essay that described the creative works of “mortals” as “organisms” or “homunculi” with their origins in “inspiration.” This man was the first to use a term for inspiration, Einfall, interchangeably with the older term Gedanken, as seen in his major theoretical work, The Musical Idea. This man’s maxim that “genius learns only from itself” and his claim that “how music sounds is not the point” are relayed in another author’s book of critical theory that praises this man’s intellectualist innovations and contains lengthy diatribes against jazz. Theodor Adorno’s Philosophy of Modern Music extensively analyzes, for 10 points, what teacher of Alban Berg and inventor of twelve-tone composition? ","answer":"ANSWER: Arnold Schoenberg <Music> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"8. The National Arts Program received royalties from the best-selling catalog of these paintings, the first ever art catalog selected by the Book-of-the-Month Club. At museum gift stores, patrons could buy a VHS narrated by Charlton Heston that discussed the creation of these paintings, which were bought in their entirety for \"many millions of dollars\" by Leonard E. B. Andrews. Former Monty Python member Michael Palin was the first to interview the subject of these works, who originally worked as a nurse for Karl Kuerner. These paintings were primarily made in the loft of a millhouse in Chadds Ford, Pennsylvania, and in cover stories of both Time and Newsweek it was noted that the artist's wife wasn't aware of them being made. One painting in this series is titled for the braids worn by the namesake model. For 10 points, name this series of works by Andrew Wyeth of a German model. ","answer":"ANSWER: Helga paintings [or The Helga Pictures; accept anything involving Andrew Wyeth's paintings of Helga Testorf] <Painting and Sculpture> 4/18/2019 Tiebreakers/Replacements - Google Docs https://docs.google.com/document/d/1lPxg-Ujut4_rc4dN7YKfx840YfEyyRpzssmOHBMNks8/edit 4/7 ACF Nationals 2019 | Packet: Tiebreakers/Replacements |Page 4 "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"9. A Japanese tradition on this day involves periodically rubbing oneself with yuzu fruit while taking a hot bath. Some Iranian celebrations of this event call for forty different edibles to be placed on a korsi. A type of hot dumpling traditionally eaten in China on this day stems from Zhang Zhongjing being alarmed by the ears of the poor. The Night of Chelleh in Iran celebrates this event,which coincides with the Chinese Dongzhi Festival. Prior to the adoption of the Gregorian Calendar, Scandinavian countries celebrated the Feast of Saint Lucy on this day. This day was the main day of celebration for a multi-day Roman holiday that started when the sun was about to enter the sign of Capricorn and featured slaves donning the clothes of free men. That holiday, Saturnalia, affected the date of Christmas. For 10 points, name this event that takes place around December 21st each year. ","answer":"ANSWER: winter solstice [or hibernal solstice; or midwinter; or longest night of the year; accept Night of Chelleh or Saint Lucy's Day or Dongzhi Festival or December 21 st or December 22 nd before mentioned; prompt on solstice] <Religion> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"0. Researchers investigating this faculty often use a test developed by William Lee, Avron Marcus, and Richard Doty known as the B-SIT. Asifa Majid is the lead author of a 2018 paper in which a cross-cultural study revealed that, for Umpila, this was the most “encodable” of the studied faculties, which accorded with Majid’s prior research finding this faculty to be particularly encodable in hunter-gatherer societies. Cultural linguists have found that most languages distinguish subjective experiences involving this faculty along hedonic lines by describing them using evaluative terms; more often, experiences involving this faculty are described in concrete, source-based terms. The almost uniformly poor link between this faculty and language has led it to be called the “muted sense.” The lowest position on Aristotle’s hierarchy of the senses is occupied by, for 10 points, what human faculty that, along with the sense of taste, gives rise to a food’s flavor? ","answer":"ANSWER: smell [or olfaction; or olfactory sense] <Social Science> 4/18/2019 Tiebreakers/Replacements - Google Docs https://docs.google.com/document/d/1lPxg-Ujut4_rc4dN7YKfx840YfEyyRpzssmOHBMNks8/edit 5/7 ACF Nationals 2019 | Packet: Tiebreakers/Replacements |Page 5 "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"[10] Name this brilliant government statistician whose relationships with his unfaithful wife Sylvia and the suffragette Valentine Wannop are the subject of a modernist tetralogy. ","answer":"ANSWER: Christopher Tietjens [accept either underlined portion] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"[10] Christopher Tietjens is the protagonist of this author’s Parade’s End. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ford Madox Ford [or Ford Hermann Hueffer] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"[10] In the second volume of the series, Tietjens is haunted by the death of this Welsh soldier, who is killed by shrapnel after Tietjens refuses to grant him leave to deal with his own unfaithful wife. ","answer":"ANSWER: O Nine Morgan <British Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"[10] The protagonist of this author’s novel Television fails to get past the first two words, “When Musset,” of his treatise on Titian. This Belgian author wrote a series of four novels called the “cycle of Marie.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Jean-Philippe Toussaint "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"[10] In this Albert Camus novel, Joseph Grand continually revises the first sentence of his book while the title crisis sweeps through the city of Oran. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Plague [or La Peste] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"[10] The title architectural historian of this novel, whose text is interspersed with photographs, describes seeing “the inadequacy of all the words I had employed” after taking an entire day to write one sentence. ","answer":"ANSWER: Austerlitz <European Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"[10] Identify this landmark 1948 Supreme Court case which outlawed restrictions that prevented homeowners from selling to members of a particular race. ","answer":"ANSWER: Shelley v. Kraemer [or Shelley v. Kraemer; or Shelley et ux. v. Kraemer et ux. McGhee et ux. v. Sipes et al.] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"[10] The Supreme Court struck down restrictive covenants on the grounds that they violated the equal protection clause of this amendment to the Constitution. ","answer":"ANSWER: Fourteenth Amendment "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"[10] Shelly was joined with McGhee v. Sipes, which concerned racial covenants in this city. Ossian Sweet was tried for murder after defending his house from a mob trying to evict him from a previously whites-only neighborhood in this city. ","answer":"ANSWER: Detroit <American History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"[10] Identify this man who helped deliver Zyklon B to concentration camps, but who also attempted to pass on details about the horrors of the Holocaust to men such as Goran von Otter. He's a character in William T. Vollmann's novel, Europe Central. ","answer":"ANSWER: Kurt Gerstein "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"[10] Gerstein was an officer in this Nazi organization, whose head was Heinrich Himmler. Soldiers in this organization wore black uniforms. ","answer":"ANSWER: SS [or Schutzstaffel] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"2. ","answer":"ANSWER: Reinhard Heydrich [or Reinhard Tristan Eugen Heydrich] <European/World History> 4/18/2019 Tiebreakers/Replacements - Google Docs https://docs.google.com/document/d/1lPxg-Ujut4_rc4dN7YKfx840YfEyyRpzssmOHBMNks8/edit 6/7 ACF Nationals 2019 | Packet: Tiebreakers/Replacements |Page 6 "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"[10] Name this no-go theorem which states that it is only possible to combine space-time and internal symmetries in a trivial way. ","answer":"ANSWER: Coleman-Mandula theorem "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"[10] The Haag-Łopuszański-Sohnius theorem generalizes the Coleman-Mandula theorem to theories with this principle, which claims that each fermion has a counterpart boson and vice versa, such as the gluon and the proposed “gluino.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Supersymmetry [or SUSY; do not prompt on “superstring”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"[10] Supersymmetry offers an appealing solution to this problem, which asks why gravity is so much weaker than the other forces. ","answer":"ANSWER: hierarchy problem <Physics> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"[10] Identify these birds, whose beaks were explored in a Pulitzer-winning 1995 book by Jonathan Weiner. ","answer":"ANSWER: Darwin's finches [or Galapagos finches; or true finches] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"[10] There are some 80 examples of species in the Bulimulus genus of these creatures on the Galapagos islands, more than the number of finches and tortoises combined. Pulmonata are a variety of these creatures that can breathe air. ","answer":"ANSWER: snails [or slugs] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"[10] David Lack dedicated his book Darwin's Finches to the Academy of Sciences in this city, home to an important collection of Galapagos specimens. Other public buildings in this city include a War Memorial that doubles as a Performing Arts Center housing the Herbst Theatre. ","answer":"ANSWER: San Francisco <Other Academic> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"[10] Identify this photographer who captured the Chicago Outlaws motorcycle club and who served as the official photographer of the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee. ","answer":"ANSWER: Danny Lyon "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"[10] In the 1970s, Lyon photographed the buildings of Lower Manhattan set to be demolished for this project, whose main towers were designed by Minoru Yamasaki. ","answer":"ANSWER: World Trade Center [prompt on Twin Towers] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"[10] A photo included in Lyon's 2016 Whitney show depicts Bill Sanders giving a man a tattoo. This other photographer made the square-format Tattooed Man at a Carnival, Maryland, one of several photographs of \"freaks.\" ","answer":"ANSWER: Diane Arbus <Other Fine Arts> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"[10] Name this art form which is the subject of a 1980 book by Roland Barthes. ","answer":"ANSWER: photography "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"[10] This Italian author of The Essence of Aesthetics suggested that photography is not quite an art because the “element of nature” remains “unconquered and ineradicable” in it. ","answer":"ANSWER: Benedetto Croce "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"[10] This Czech-born philosopher who did much of his work in Brazil argued that the physical nature of the photographic apparatus prevents photography from directly capturing reality in Towards a Philosophy of Photography. ","answer":"ANSWER: Vilém Flusser <Philosophy> 4/18/2019 Tiebreakers/Replacements - Google Docs https://docs.google.com/document/d/1lPxg-Ujut4_rc4dN7YKfx840YfEyyRpzssmOHBMNks8/edit 7/7 ACF Nationals 2019 | Packet: Tiebreakers/Replacements |Page 7 "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"8. ","answer":"ANSWER: Universal Postal Union [or UPU; or Union postale universelle] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"5. ","answer":"ANSWER: Alibaba [or Alibaba Group Holding Limited] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"[10] A \"mighty\" one of these products, invented by New Jersey resident Jayme Smaldone, has become a symbol of unfair UPU rates because it's cheaper to ship counterfeit ones from China. ","answer":"ANSWER: mug [or travel coffee mug; accept Mighty Mug] <Current Events> "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"[10] Name this profession whose members are “conservative realists” according to a book titled for its members “and the state,” which is a foundational text in the study of the “relations” between this profession and civil society. ","answer":"ANSWER: military [accept soldiers or service members or servicemen or answers indicating member of the armed forces; accept The Soldier and the State or military-civil relations or civil-military relations] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"[10] This political scientist argued for hands-off civilian control of the military in The Soldier and the State. In a 1993 Foreign Affairs article, he wrote that future wars would involve a “clash of civilizations.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Samuel Huntington [or Samuel Phillips Huntington] "},{"tournament":"ACF Nationals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Difficult College","round":"Tiebreakers","question":"[10] In Armed Servants, this Duke professor used a principal-agent framework to challenge Huntington’s theory of civil-military relations. This thinker argued for civilian monitoring to avoid military “shirking.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Peter Feaver [or Peter Douglas Feaver] <Social Science>"}]
